this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software digital ocean is the easiest
cloud platform to deploy manage and
scale applications of any size we're
moving infrastructure friction and
providing predictability so developers
and their teams can deploy faster and
focus on building software that
customers love with thousands of
in-depth tutorials in an active
community we provide the support you
need digitalocean stands out of the
crowd due to its simplicity and high
performance with no billing surprises
try digitalocean for free by getting a
one hundred dollar infrastructure credit
at doco / SC radio hello this is jeremy
jeong for a software engineering radio
today i have david Calavera with me
david is the CTO of net lafha where he
and his team are building a platform for
deploying and automating modern web
projects previously he was a core member
of the docker engine project David also
built enterprise tools for github and
has contributed to numerous open source
projects including go JRuby and many
others today I'll be speaking with David
about zero downtime migrations and
rollbacks with kubernetes after this
episode if you want to learn more about
kubernetes you can check out episode 246
with john wilkes on Borg and kubernetes
or episode 319 with Nicole Hubbard on
migrating from VMs to kubernetes David
welcome to software engineering radio
first I'd like to discuss migrations and
basically defining what they are so
first what is a migration well basically
a migration is a way to move software
from one version to another and if there
really depends on what you're trying to
migrate it could be more complicated or
less complicated it also depends on if
you're trying to migrate from an old
system to a very new system which is
this case basically
could you give some examples of what's
considered a migration versus just a
regular change to a system yes just
fully migrations involve changing the
fundamental concepts in the system so in
our day to day developing software for
instance we can deploy minimal changes
in a continuous manner and those will
just be considered like regular deploys
where your system changes but it doesn't
change the condition the mental concepts
within your system when we talk about
migrations we're talking about a change
in fundamental concepts within your
systems or even replacing the whole
system with a different one you describe
fundamental concepts could you give an
example of what a fundamental concept
might be yes for example let's say
you're you have an application that has
been built with trails and it has become
a model is right if you wanna split that
application in different micro-services
that would be a fundamental change right
your your change in like the way that
your your application is the structure
will change in the way that the
application is gonna be deployed that's
what when we talk about migrations are
they atomic operations where the entire
system switches from the old system to
the new system at the same time that's
that's a good question and it really
depends on your discus this is actually
part of my talk will try to discuss
concepts like certainty right when you
perform a big migration you need to make
sure that what you're migrating to has
the same certainty then why do you have
before for instance you need to make
sure that that you know that you're
something like actually has the same
behaviors or even need to know that how
your new system is gonna fail right and
then does can affect how you perform
that migration I'm not a big fan of
migrations were to basically replace
wants to move with the other and this is
this is this is also gonna be in my talk
where I explain how we perform this
creation in an incremental way where
at some point in time and actually
during several months we were running
both systems at the same time so we can
predict well what's gonna happen with a
new system once we put it in production
for a hundred percent of our juicers you
were describing about being able to
predict what can happen with the new
system is that because you were running
both systems at the same time yes we run
the city say that we define metrics and
pieces of information within the new
system that will allow us to make sure
that that it was working correctly and
we also define some scenarios where we
decided that the system was not working
correctly and we designed some
strategies to be able to roll back to
the old system while the new system was
still running at the same time right
what are some examples of things that
could go wrong during a migration well
there are many things that can go wrong
and this is this is actually one of my
favorite topics and and it's very well
described in in a book that that I
always recommend people called the a top
principle and it talks about trade-offs
between efficiency and and
untruthfulness right when you're running
a big migration to in a system you need
to find a balance between the efficiency
of migrating to this net the new system
because obviously what you wanna you're
in most cases you're trying to get rid
of a system that doesn't work for you
for you just guess anymore so you want
to be efficient and undo that migration
as soon as possible but on the other
hand you need to be thorough to make
sure that the new system is actually
gonna work in a way that you expect
right because obviously when when you're
introduced in a new system you're
introducing new unknowns entry into your
whole architecture right what was the
the book that you recommend it's called
the hetero principle and
it is ett oh okay the echo principle and
it does it walkthrough
you said the trade-offs between how fast
you move towards the new system but
still making sure that it works yeah
it's what it calls the efficiency and
thorough nets trade-off right you need
to balance the efficiency of doing
something and and the thoroughness of
doing that that same thing right and
it's look it's only about software
engineering and it talks a lot about
industries like aviation or like
manufacturing as you say that we're
actually the stakes are higher right and
they need to be they need to find these
balance in a more precise way right so
there's a lot of lessons that we can
actually take from other industries that
are described in the book yeah exactly
when a team encounters errors or
failures during a migration what are
their options again this really depends
on the migration and what and your
system my my favorite tools to to
actually be thorough about migration
some turbine issues during during these
kind of migrations are are applying
several patterns that are very well
described in in many books and articles
but the first one is the circuit breaker
other where you have some code running
in inside your application that's able
to decide when to stop doing something
depending on the success or failure of
this operation so let's say for instance
it's very common for network operations
right so let's say you you are talking
with a with a third party service and
you're sending HTTP requests and this
third party service goes down so you
have in place a circuit breaker that
allows you to stop sending those
requests to the third party well it's
done and at the same time it has some
logic to to really clearly try to see if
the support other party is back aligned
right this actually forces you to to
think about
the consequences of this party going out
right and then do you have to do you
have to add it to your code logic to
make sure that when this third part is
down your users are not affected or you
have some way to actually interrupt the
traffic or some way to actually handle
that in a graceful manner right and
that's one of my favorite tools
everything with you are nullified that
involves having it having to talk with
third parties is protected with with
these kind of circuit breakers different
tools that the wheels use involve for
instance being able to send the same
requests to two different services like
you will be in this case where after
sending the request and recipient
responses you you can compare those
responses and decide whether the
responses from the new system are what
you were expecting and or not right and
then you can decide whether you you
wanna keep sending more requests to the
new service or not depending on the
behavior of of this of the system a
point in time right and this is a actual
use and I mentioned that this is a
pattern described by Martin Fowler but I
don't really remember I never remember
the name of the pattern but I can I can
point you to a couple of open-source
projects that implement this pattern and
one was build at github and it's called
scientist so if you go to github
organization and github there is a
project called scientist and it
basically implements this pattern and
allows you to to send two requests to
two different systems and then compare
the response and decide what what to do
depending on whether the response is
match or not I see and this is something
that could apply not just to migrations
but like you were saying
anytime you're dependent on a third
party service or a system you think may
go down yeah or maybe you're you're
changing
a big piece of code within your
application and you want to make sure
that that the behavior is still the same
right you could apply this this pattern
and just this library for for this case
to what you want to make sure that that
actually changes within your code or can
really affect the system right and with
this um I'm not sure what the pattern is
is called but this set up where you make
the two requests to do two different
systems and wait for the correct result
from each does this mean that these
services always need to be stateless
that's that's a question the easiest way
to actually apply this is with the
stylus service right because when you
when you're dealing with a stateful
services it means that you're saving
some kind of some kind of data with both
and it really depends on you and your
implementation I've used this pattern
with a stateful service services were
both branches of my code were like
storing data in two different places and
then at the same time when when the
application read data it also read the
data from from those two different
places and then compared the data and
make sure that that is actually the same
data that the application is suspected
hmm
you would have needed basically two data
stores and they would need to always be
in sync in order to get the correct
answer yes exactly right
I obviously when you're dealing with the
stateful services in it's more
preparation and unit you need to think
about that case because obviously it it
may also involve can be some kind of
migration after after if you you know
that the code works correctly or not and
things like that right right and it's
small more involved that than dealing
with stateful with a stateless services
but it could still work right I seen
Next when would you up to apply fixes on
top of a migration that didn't go well
versus choosing to perform a rollback
what they tried to do in those cases is
I tried to define a threshold as
expected behavior in natural rights
right and this is this is also something
that that you can do with with libraries
like scientist where you can say if I
get this kind of error this these are
always suspected and if I'd forget that
different at all and it's not expected
and then I and it perform a rollback or
do something something about it that's
different than than just handle in there
right in in our case and it's something
that I'm gonna include in my talk the
errors were very well defined because we
we knew what their expected errors are
and with the unexpected errors or not
it's know basically everything that was
that didn't trigger a success political
scheduling in inside kubernetes was an
error that we could not handle and it
was not acceptable
an errors that that work out cause
inside the application that well we were
grinding in kubernetes where errors that
do we accept it so those are if we sell
some of those errors with the central
bank but during this migration we had to
roll by two or three times because we
expect we bump into issues with
kubernetes that we didn't expected and
in those cases we will roll back to the
old system completely in the case of
your application you decided that for
your own application code it was okay if
there were problems because you would
apply fixes on top of that yeah but if
it was at the infrastructure level at
the kubernetes level that the difficulty
in finding the problem was may be so
high that it was better to rollback
rather than attempt to apply effects on
top of the infrastructure
yeah since we were migrating from a more
traditional service that was running
inside different machines to something
running inside kubernetes we knew that
like every error we could find that was
due to kubernetes it was something that
we didn't know how to handle Jeff and
then in those cases we decided robot
could
fine what a rollback is yeah so
basically that without Walberg I I mean
we stopped sending traffic to the new
service completely and then the traffic
that we had sent to the new service that
fail due to the the issues that we have
we bump into was reply on the all
service
I see due to the nature of the
application you were able to identify
exactly which requests to the kubernetes
setup had failed and then replay them on
the old system and so the customer was
never necessarily aware that there was
actually a failure yeah exactly what are
some of the inherent difficulties in
rollbacks in comparison to migrations
actually identifying if you can reply
requests or not is it's usually very
complicated in our case we we designed
the system from the beginning in a way
where we could actually identify those
requests even before we decide to to
migrate to a new system we kept track of
those operations so for us was was not
as hard as the two identified in which
requests were failing and why and if and
whether we could replay them on the old
system around but usually the challenges
when you when you decide to do a
rollback to from it from our migration
like this or that do you need to to deal
with this uncertainty of what to do with
with the operations that fail due to the
new system right and if you use tools
like circuit breakers or libraries like
scientist those those force you to
actually think about rollback situations
right so like in a way they helped you
to find what to do in case of failure
which is always very useful when you
need to do robots how would you say the
risks of a rollback compared to a
migration I think if your errors are
well-defined their risks are lower
because you are going
back to a system that you already know
but you need to make sure that you
understand the implications of errors in
the new system other than the types of
operations are identifying the
operations that need to be dealt with
when they fail are there any other
things that are more difficult with a
rollback like for example anything to do
with a database or something like that
yeah like that really depends on on your
system and obviously those different
different systems will have different
challenges during migrations are and
Paul bags but that's that's more
depending on and which can application
your you're dealing with right some
organizations have a philosophy of
always applying fixes and never rolling
back do you have any thoughts on this I
think it depends on your velocity and
how fast you can apply fixes versus how
fast you can roll back to to a state
that you know that is safe to roll back
sure if you if you have a very
well-defined continuous delivery
pipeline and you're capable enough to
identify errors and apply fixes as fast
as possible that could be a very good
strategy to always apply fix this and
move forward if you're not so sure about
your continuous delivery pipeline or it
takes more time to actually release new
code then then rolling back to all codes
then in those cases is probably gonna be
easier for gitarama
it really it depends on your
infrastructure and how you you architect
your release management processes and in
the case of the migration had natla phi
the troubleshooting or debugging the
problems and kubernetes you made the
decision that it would require too much
time to identify the problem and that
that was appropriate yeah since we
weren't migrated into a system that was
still
very unknown for us as a production
system we decided that actually stop
stop juice in the system completely was
safer than trying to trace the the
causes of the errors and try to fix them
while the system was still running right
I'd like to talk about downtime how
would you define downtime in the context
of a migration downtime is basically
time that your juicers are being
affected by an issue and it it does the
decimal which can I issue like there are
many ways to to have downtime in our
case in the case of magnify for instance
with the fine downtime at the city level
if customer cannot serve their their web
project that's a time that's a very
traditional way to to identify downtime
were like well if I website additional
accessible there is a downtime right but
we also identified downtime actually was
one of the reasons why we did this
migration the process were one of our
juicers tries to deploy the website and
and they cannot do it because our system
is down right so that we also define
downtime in that regard so during a
project deployment we allows users to
run some arbitrary code so they can
execute tasks to build their their
projects and if they cannot do that at
any point of time
that's downtime for us to do right what
makes zero downtime migration or
rollback more challenging I think the
challenge is is identifying how to how
to make sure that juicers don't actually
perceive and any issues during any point
in time right and in in our case for
instance if if someone tries to deploy
and something is broken inside our
system and they cannot deploy we need to
uh we need to do something to ensure
that those deploys goes through
so if if someone tries to run some code
with a project and there is an error or
because our infrastructure is down we
need to make a decision about what to do
with ourselves right right well what are
your thoughts on systems that have
planned maintenance windows versus
systems that perform zero down time
migrations I don't think I have opinions
I'm curious about reasons why people
decide to to have maintenance windows
and I'm sure there are very good reasons
we we actually completely unrelated to
this migration project we we have a
maintenance issue where we stopped a
system for I think it was like two
minutes
mmm but during those two minutes
actually within any any requests to
those to that service so actually no one
knows it okay in that case was because
we're trying to migrate an API from a
third-party provider from one version to
another and it's it's a stateful service
so we couldn't we couldn't have mixed
requests between one version of the API
and the other so we needed to actually
cut all the requests to this third-party
provider so to ensure that we didn't get
any mixed requests between versions and
then start all the new requests with the
new version of the API right I see so in
that case we had a very small
maintenance window and we actually set
it for five minutes and it it was it was
shorter than that it's it was like two
minutes but in that case that forces to
actually have that that maintenance and
it really there are introduced cases
we're like you actually need to do
things like that and all of them are
usually justified and I think that at
this point in time no no one actually
wants to have a maintenance with the
effects users and um prevents people
from from users from using your your
research right the reason I asked the
question is is more determining when it
makes sense to do kind of like what you
did where you make the decision that the
system is just going to be down for a
few minutes or whatever that timeframe
is versus there may be cases where
attempting to perform a migration
without downtime is actually from an
engineering perspective very difficult
so when does it make sense from a cost
perspective to just sort of take the
head and say like okay we're going to be
down for 10 minutes versus spending 40
engineering hours making sure that we do
a migration with no downtime yeah it
really depends on on each case right I
don't think there is a general rule to
say like oh this this kind of a shion's
need to be always like knit require some
time time or some maintenance window
these are the ones don't write I don't
need in our rule just to apply there it
really depends on on each case next I'd
like to talk about the app that you're
migrating to the kubernetes system
what does at a high level the
application you're migrating do yeah so
it's very intense interesting story
because it's not a traditional stateless
application which is basically this
strong kubernetes workload this is the
system that we try to make well we
migrated to kubernetes is the system
that runs the arbitrary code that people
give us to build their projects so in
the old system is when we got a request
to build a project we sent that request
into a queue and then there was a there
was one of our services picked messages
from that queue and then schedule some
docker containers and ran run that code
inside Doka Doka containers right and
for different reasons we we had several
issues with that and one of the most
evident for us was that
we don't have a nice way to scale that
service so if for some reason we get an
insane amount of requests to that
service at any point of time it was it
was very complicated for us to actually
scale that in a way that didn't affect
Jews right so for people in those cases
basically they experienced delays deploy
in their websites right and within some
investigations we we had several
alternatives and we decided to go with
kubernetes after several tests because
the scheduler did most of the heavy
lifting for us with this some tests and
it worked pretty well
and it also it also gave us the
autoscaler capabilities that we didn't
have so in if during peak hours we
needed us schedule
I'd say 30 pots or 50 pots Delta scalar
would do that automatically for us and
during non-peak hours like let's say
during weekends the autoscaler would
decrease the number of pods in the
cluster for us directly right so that
was something that was very appealing
for us so we replace this all system
where we sent messages to this queue and
then there was a service running and
like listening for messages in the queue
to a system where we send messages to
the kubernetes scale or to a schedule
new pods and then the scheduler
basically scheduled these pods with with
the software that that we implemented to
write to write the full definition into
into coronaries and then then execute
the user's code inside inside those pods
right the original system you were using
that was running on VMs and using
containers how are you performing the
manual scaling so minor scale miss
Kaling was basically as increment in the
number of the ends that were connected
to this gear did you have custom
software you wrote to determine what
your load was
and how much to scale we actually did
not like we had some metrics and we had
some alerts and we knew when based on
those metrics we knew when we had to
scale the system but it was still very
uncertain to us when we had to do it
right it was a very reactive process
where where we've got these
notifications and then we were like okay
now we're gonna we're gonna increase the
number of VMs but then we never knew
when we could decrease the number of VMs
or like obviously we also had the
scenarios where we increase the capacity
of the cluster and then we actually with
it an idiot right you had some metrics
and some alerts but ultimately it was
engineers on your team that decided
whether to increase the number of
instances or maybe even decrease the
number of instances yeah exactly a kind
of a high level can you describe what
kubernetes does and what pods are in the
context of that yeah so kubernetes is a
distributed system that takes job
definitions and then given the job a job
definition it could be a job the finish
you could be just run these a web
application or write it basically run
this process which is it could be just a
go process or a rails web application or
like any kind of process that you that
you wanna define and then this schedule
the scheduler decides to put this
process into what are called pods and
Apollo is basically a group of
containers together so a pod is to
slowly the process that you wanna run
that you gave the desk alder in the
definition and then some side color
containers to help that process for
instance you have a container to do
login aggregation or do you have a
container to twist extract matrix from
from the process that that you are
running and so on right and that's
that's a pol is basically a group
of containers that work together to make
sure that your process actually works as
expected
he described how kubernetes provides
things like logging aggregation or
extracting metrics were you using the
same software to do that that you were
with the previous system or was this
something new no it was the same it was
the same software we run the same
infrastructure for for logging
aggregation and metrics than we did
before but the only difference is that
we had two architecture in a different
way but at the end all that information
end up in the same in the same systems
SC so for the most part the actual
application code you wrote was untouched
with both architectures is that correct
yeah that is correct were you making use
of a vendors implementation of
kubernetes or were you managing the
instance yourself so we use Google
containers engine and that's something
that we talk a lot about it there is
always a trade-off between buy-in versus
building and we could have managed it
ourselves but then we would have also
introducing more unknowns to our system
since we we had no used kubernetes at
this scale before right so managing
ourselves the cluster would mean also
that we would need to manage at Citi and
we would need to manage the whole
lifecycle of the cluster and so on and
since we are still a small team we
decided to to actually go with a
provider that could do all that for us
so we could focus on on our application
and actually deliver like the service to
our users for developers that work at
nullified did this migration change
anything for them did we had to change a
little bit the way that we deploy these
services to kubernetes because before
when we had them in neutral machines
they were like long-running services so
the deployment process
was to put the new binaries in the
spiritual machines and then restart the
services in a graceful way and then when
we migrated to kubernetes we moved to us
to a system where those services were
not running continuously all the time so
the kubernetes scheduler starts the
process and instead of being
long-running processes it's a short
running process that is still that's the
same logic but it does it for every time
we we schedule a job in in the content
in the cluster when you decided to
perform the migration how did you
prepare to perform a migration without
downtime yeah so most of the preparation
came from from ensuring that that we we
could roll back to the old system and
that we could extract enough information
from for us to understand why the new
system was not working and we put in
place a system with with the tools and
and techniques that that we discussed
before so so we could decide what to do
when when we bump into issues with with
the new system and that was most of most
of the preparation that that we did for
this migration it was basically ensuring
that no matter what like people
shouldn't could not be affected by us
trying to migrate to the new system and
and we had enough information to
actually the back to the new system and
and find find the issues that we vampy
to did you choose a small percentage of
users to migrate or how did you start
the process yeah so we started just
juicing it ourselves so we everything
that like every single web property that
nullifier owns runs on magnify so it's
it's very good for us to actually to be
able to test these things because we
have many projects that actually run an
unmanned defy so and it's not only
especially
for in these in this case but everything
we we do first we we tried ourselves to
make sure that it works that we're
satisfied with the with it and that that
everything works out the experiment with
with our use cases and then we just
feature flags to to be able to to
release or to be able to to be able to
move traffic from one system to another
in a controlled manner
so at first we we just move one percent
of the traffic to this new system and
then observe what happened and then if
if everything when everything was
correct we we increased that percentage
to ten percent and then and so on right
and we actually at some point we
actually increase the traffic to to a
hundred percent and and we had after
increase in the the traffic to a hundred
percent we we bump into issues that we
had not been to before and we had to
actually decrease the not the percent of
traffic to zero and then start over
right
I see so you and AB dog who did it
yourself
and then gradually increased the users
that were migrated to the new system but
it wasn't until you had actually
performed a full migration that you
started to experience problems yeah we
experienced all different problems and
actually its problem was manifested in
the in different states of of the
migration when these problems were
happening when you were getting them
from your metrics what would a user have
experienced during this period so for a
user they will see one of the deploys
for their products fail and
automatically as soon as they deploy
fail a new deploy was a scandal like
right away so for them what they will
see is that something inside nullified
will fail and then nullify itself
decided to trigger a new deploy right
away
and when we triggered this new deploy it
was it was triggered in the old system
where we knew that that that deploy
should work as expected right
I see so for a user during this period
they most likely would not have even
noticed that there was a problem
happening with the migration yeah
exactly
well so you said there were metrics that
you were following was there a very
large percentage of builds that were
failing or was it just a small amount er
we bump into a couple of issues were a
big percentage of bills start failing
because of this saturation inside the
containers so the since we allow people
to run arbitrary code and they this this
code usually involves creating many
files and we bump into issues where
where people would saturate disks and
then Wales's that start failing and that
all that actually we only discovered
that when we turn a hundred percent of
the traffic into the new system and so
in that case like a large number of
people we actually bump into that issue
and then there deploys were
automatically reschedule but then for
other issues like not many people
actually bump into them and and some
some issues also were all involved that
the deploys were delayed so instead of
being deployed like in 30 seconds or
less maybe was deployed in like three or
five minutes three four five minutes
something like that right
and as you were seeing these metrics
occur I guess in this case like you said
it was over saturation of the disks in
most cases did you know the source of
the problems or were you just aware of
the fact that there was a problem most
of the cases we didn't know the source
of the problem and we had to do some
investigation in that in the the case of
the desaturation was was actually very
funny because we realized that this this
saturation issue
a problem with docker that I try to fix
long time ago when I was still working a
docker and I never fixed because we
never knew I why it wasn't what we had
reports of people saying that some
commands God stack and actually like
called segmentation faults hunger but we
never knew why and we tried we would try
different things and and we never we
never fixed it and future versions of
docker actually work around this problem
because they drug load the whole engine
with women when docker moved from from
having the schedule the container
scheduler inside the docker engine to to
juice container the-- the whole system
was proved Willian and unlike that
problem disappear and I think until even
today wool container engine still just
an old version of docker
that still has this problem right mmm
so when when the disk get saturated and
kubernetes was kubernetes trying to
perform some health checks it uses a
command in docker called docker PS just
to check if the containers are running
so the disk was saturated and then you
kubernetes was trying to run docker PS
which caused docker PS to hang forever
and then kubernetes decide to kill
containers because it thought that they
were stale and it was very funny because
like when i was working a talker like
wait we never knew why docker PS could
hang at all yeah I didn't like and then
when we bump into this I was like oh my
god this is you and now I understand it
so is it like you were trying to search
for a solution and then you came across
your old issue you had posted or
something like that yeah there was a
long thread on that issue because it was
open like I think it was like 2014 or
something like that
mmm many people have not been to it
and the issue the description was
basically docker PS hangs or unknown
results yeah it's very general yeah so
like different people have up into a
different people have tried to to find
the root cause no one knew like why
happened but we knew it happen and then
yeah yeah at the end it happened to me
and we were able to understand it but at
this point docker doesn't use the same
code to do docker PS like that's not a
problem anymore anymore so when you were
performing the migration to kubernetes
that code that had this problem doesn't
exist anymore
no it does still exist in all versions
of docker and Google actually Google
container engine still uses a version of
docker that's affected by this bag oh I
see I see
so just to make sure I understand so you
were saying the when the disks get
saturated in this case it's because a
bunch of files are being created within
the same container this causes some kind
of problem with docker does in does the
container become unresponsive at that
point I think the container becomes
unresponsive I'm not completely sure
about that mm-hmm
but docker PS which is the command that
lists all the containers that docker is
running it becomes unresponsive and
kubernetes uses Tucker peers to do
health checks inside the cluster right
so kubernetes thought that something was
wrong in in the cluster and it end up
restarting the docker diamond inside the
class alright I see I see I think when
when you restart the docker daemon in
this specific version of Locker because
it was still an old version it killed
all the containers that were running in
in the cluster because they they all
when it would run docker PS it would
just hang so it would assume that all
the containers must be down
exactly I see how did you identify these
problems after you had decided to do the
rollback because the problem you said
only manifested when you were at a
hundred percent load yeah what we did in
those cases was was we started trying to
reproduce the problem with her own
properties and our own projects and
since when we knew that it only
manifested with and with a hundred
percent of the load we try to we try to
generate download for our own projects
so we we run some experiments with our
own projects too to be able to generate
the same amount of load we saw when the
dish was saturated and then when we
managed to reproduce that with with our
own requests we were able to trace it
into into this this issue hmm I see when
you decided to do the migration did you
perform any kind of load testing on the
containers beforehand with it with it uh
there's some blood testing and and
everything everything looked correct but
obviously the amount of load that you
can expect Oh always changes and like we
can never predict what users are gonna
are gonna do during traffic hours and
when the system is in production but we
did run some load testing before we
started the whole migration just to make
sure that content the kubernetes
together could actually handle the load
and everything looked correct as we
didn't actually bump into any of these
issues that we bump after the migration
so after fixing this issue you performed
a second migration attempt did you
encounter any issues after that
we encounter an issue with the
autoscaler and we we end up rolling back
the version of kubernetes that we were
running and that seemed to fix the issue
and we end up just just in an all
version of kubernetes instead of the
newer ones and i think that the most
recent one solves that problem but we
haven't tested yet and this problem with
the autoscaler you didn't encounter that
with the first migration exactly and it
was also an issue that that only appear
when we started running all our traffic
through the cluster and it was because
the autoscaler
was was not actually scaling the size of
the cluster correctly so in this case
users would see delays under deploys and
it would basically was that the the
queue that the scheduler keeps in at CB
was growing but the autoscaler was not
expand increasing the number the number
of pulse in the in the cluster
accordingly to the scale so people who
the experience basically delays under
deploys but it was not something that
was that was not critical because I at
the end like all the deploys actually
went through and I mean we only
experienced it when we try to to update
the version of kubernetes and then right
away we decided to just roll back the
version of kubernetes done that that's
it's time to fix the problem I see so
you did the first migration on a version
of kubernetes you rolled back fix the
problem where kubernetes was doing the
health check and seeing all the
containers were down because of the
command failing then you addressed that
issue and then you migrate it again
but on the second migration you used a
newer version of kubernetes no we make
it
and then that that it was stable for for
some time in some way running in
production and then at some point we
decided to to update the version of
kubernetes and then I think when we when
we bump into this new issue and then in
this case we we only had to to downgrade
the version of kubernetes but we still
had the old service running and we did
move some people some traffic to the old
system while we were trying to figure
out why it was not working correctly
I see so when you decided to try
upgrading kubernetes you still had the
old version running the VMS available we
kept the cluster around for some time
just as a precaution mm-hmm and actually
it was a it was a good idea at the end
but then after after that after so we
know that that the other issue again we
kept the cluster around for a while and
then we just remove it how long did you
keep the old system before deciding to
close it I think it was it was between
two weeks and a month after you had let
the system run complete with all traffic
going to the new system
yeah then you made the decision that it
seemed stable enough to shut it down
yeah looking back is there anything you
would have done differently to try and
catch the failures you had during
migrations it's it's hard to say at the
end it took us longer than than we
expected to the dis my Gration and we
could have we could have taken a
different approaches instead of this one
but I I don't think the other approaches
would have been just incident-free
we just don't know well we have happen
in those cases and even though even
though it took us longer than than we
expected our the system is much more
stable than it was before right now we
also have better information about what
happens inside the system just because
kubernetes provides much more
information and insights then we have
before and
and we have also said like since we are
more confident about the system and we
have more information about it we can
actually make better decisions I in the
in the past few months we have seen the
load of the traffic increasing a lot and
if we have been in the old system our
reaction will have been basically to
just increase increase the capacity but
now since since we we have in a very
position to do auto scaling and we have
more information we can actually stop
before reacting and actually think about
the consequences and think about why
this system is behaving in the same in
the way that's behaving and so on and
now with kubernetes you've in a way
outsourced the decision on whether to
scale up or down that all just happens
automatically yeah exactly right and
like since we we know that this that
that's gonna happen we can actually look
it into the data and see why is
happening and see like and actually
we're very inform about when it happens
and why it happens right here was about
a month ago we had an issue with with a
customer that was trying to use our
system to do mine bitcoins right oh so
like in that case like the autoscaler
just kick in and it started like
increasing the size of the cluster and
then we could go in to see what was
running inside the cluster and what
actually triggered that at the scaling
and then we saw that there was some
someone that was trying to mined
bitcoins in the system right and like
and we could actually spend the time
into looking into a land and saying why
what's happening and actually the rest
of the our customers were not affected
because the system just increased the
capacity and it and everyone every
single deploy went through and and
nothing happened for any other customers
but in the old system that would have
caused a lot of delays in for other
customers it would have caused us to
actually
try to like how to scale the system
manually we have caused us to actually
having to do a lot of things that we
don't have to do yeah it's so in this
case it seems like kubernetes actually
helped you prevent yourself from
becoming a Bitcoin miner yeah exactly
it's because since we know that that the
system is gonna handle doing all these
automatic operations for us we can
actually spend the time into into
looking into the reasons why this is
happening right so overall it sounds
like kubernetes allowed you to use your
resources more efficiently it also gave
you auto scaling it also gave you more
information more insight into seeing
where problems are or why things might
be scaling up overall are you happy with
the decision to migrate to kubernetes
yeah we're happy yep do you have any
recommendations for people who are
considering a migration to kubernetes
there are a lot of resources around
these days a guide that I'd really like
is called I think it's called kubernetes
the hard way and it explains how to
actually set everything up and it's it's
very thorough dip dye into kubernetes
and it helps you understand a lot a lot
of the system and how it works and I
think that's that's very fundamental
fundamental aspect to to actually move
to kubernetes even if you decide not to
manage it yourself but that can also
help you make those those kind of
decisions right mm-hmm
so that's the book that you maybe read
initially when you were making your
decision yeah it's not a book it
I think it have it's in a repository and
it's it's it's a guide so like in a
github repository but it's it's it's a
very it's a very good trade I see okay
we'll be sure to put that in the show
notes are there any general
recommendations you have for teams that
are undergoing zero downtime migrations
or
max I would recommend people to try to
understand the reasons why your system
is failing also try to understand the
reasons why your new system might fail
and actually having those those pieces
of information will guide people into
into writing their software and writing
software that is more resilient
resilient to failure so just in a
general sense make sure that you employ
tactics like for example you had the I
think what was the term the circuit
breaker pattern or employing a pattern
such as the one you described where you
send the same calls to do two different
services and see which make sure that
both succeed and just give you ways of
having more information so that you you
know why there's a failure and you'll be
prepared if there is a problem yeah
exactly
finally how can people follow you and
see what you're working on next I'm on
Twitter people can follow me there my
last my handle is my last name Calavera
and I'm also github with the same handle
and then if people have questions they
can email me to table at nullify that
count here and for people who want to
hear more about the migration and net
laughs I you have a talk coming up could
you just say briefly what that's about
yeah I have a talk coming up at the
velocity curve in San Jose next
Wednesday the talk is basically the
story about this migration and a highway
and also like basically the same
concepts that we we talk here today in
the talk I'll probably try to also
public a blog post after the the
conference talking a little bit about
about all this year some people might be
able to read it online
great so when this show airs the the
conference talk I believe the video
should be posted by then so we'll be
sure to post those in the notes as well
well David thank you so much for coming
on the show thanks for having me
this is Jeremy Joan for a software
engineering radio thank you for
listening thanks for listening to Nessie
radio an educational program brought to
you by Triple E software magazine for
more about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at Etsy -
radio net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of SU radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5 thanks for
listening